callawaygolf.com 2004-06-06

# 

At Callaway Golf, we are committed to respecting your privacy (click here to find out who we are). As a visitor to one of our websites, we only want to contact you if you wish to be contacted by us.  With that in mind, we offer you the following details of how we gather, use, share and protect the information collected at this website.

  1. What kinds of information does Callaway Golf collect?
  2. What are cookies?
  3. Why does Callaway Golf collect this information and how is it used?
  4. Where does Callaway Golf store this information and is it secure?
  5. How long will Callaway Golf store this Personal Information?
  6. Does Callaway Golf share this information with anyone?
  7. What is the process for reviewing and correcting information?
  8. Does Callaway Golf offer links to other websites?
  9. What about Personal Information received from 3rd parties?
  10. What about the privacy of children?
  11. What happens if Personal Information is not provided?
  12. How can I stop receiving communications from Callaway Golf?
  13. What happens when changes are made to this Privacy Policy?
  14. When was the Privacy Policy last updated and when do those changes take effect?

**1\. What kinds of information does Callaway Golf collect?**   
Callaway Golf websites can collect information about you in a number of ways. One way we do this is by directly requesting information from you (as on a sweepstakes or contest entry form, as part of a product registration page, in response to a survey or on similar webpages where you are able to enter information into data fields and then send this information back to Callaway Golf). You may be given the opportunity to voluntarily provide us with your name, address, phone number, fax number, email address, and similar information about you as an individual. We may also ask you questions about your golf game, your buying preferences or your lifestyle. We refer to all of this information as your "Personal Information."

Another way we collect information is by automatically recording information about your visit to our websites. For example, we might collect data regarding your activity while on our websites or record the webpages that you have chosen to visit. This is a common practice for many websites on the Internet. The information collected does not personally identify you, but may be helpful to us for marketing purposes or improving the services we offer. We refer to this type of information as "General Data." For example, we automatically log visitors' domain and IP addresses (a unique string of numbers that identifies a computer on the Internet). At times, this General Data may be combined with the Personal Information that you have provided.  As described below, we also use cookies to enable the website to personalize your future visits and to help you navigate.

From time to time, you may also be given the opportunity to give us feedback about our products or services or to post messages for others to read. Sometimes this is done anonymously. Other times your name or other identifying features may be attached. This process will always be voluntary and we will explain to you how the information will be used whenever we ask for it.

Callaway Golf intends to give you as much control as possible over your Personal Information. In general, you can visit Callaway Golf on the Internet without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information about yourself. There are times, however, when we may need your Personal Information in order to respond to or process your requests or to allow you to participate in online promotions. It is our intent to let you know before we collect information from you on the Internet. 

If you choose to give Callaway Golf Personal Information via the Internet, it is also our intent to let you know how we will use such information. If you tell us that you do not wish to have this Personal Information used as a basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes.

 **2\. What are cookies?**  
"Cookies" are pieces of information that a website transfers to your hard drive for record-keeping and other purposes. Cookies allow the website to remember important information that will make your use of the site more convenient and efficient. Like many websites, Callaway Golf uses cookies for a variety of purposes in order to improve your online experience. For example, we track the total number of visitors to our site on an anonymous aggregate basis. We may also employ cookies so that we remember you when you return to the site, to keep track of the webpages that you have looked at, to administer certain online contests, sweepstakes and promotions, and to help customize your Callaway Golf web experience. We also may associate Personal Information with a cookie file in those instances.

Use the options in your web browser if you do not wish to receive a cookie or if you wish to set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. Click on the "Help" section of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you disable all cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all the features offered on Callaway Golf websites.

 **3\. Why does Callaway Golf collect this information and how is it used?**  
We need this information to help us improve our services to you; we want to make it easier to tailor our products and services to your particular needs. We also want you to have the most enjoyable Internet experience possible.

With that in mind, Callaway Golf collects Personal Information and General Data in order to:

  * Make the website easier for you to use by not having to enter information more than once. 
  * Provide information faster. 
  * Create content more relevant to you. 
  * Adjust the website to your personal preferences. 
  * Conduct contests, sweepstakes and promotions. 
  * Help you quickly find products, services or information available from Callaway Golf. 
  * Make improvements to the website. 
  * Assess general trends within the website. 
  * Alert you to new products, contests, sweepstakes, special offers, updated information and other services that Callaway Golf thinks might be of interest to you. This might be done through direct contact with you or by customized postings on our websites.  Where you have given us your permission we also might authorize other companies to contact you directly. 
  * Enable you to use certain customized features and to save information for later visits to the website. 
  * Create and deliver other similar business-related features and services. 
  * Offer you occasional opportunities to provide us with feedback about our products or services.

If you elect to receive Callaway Golf-related email by opting-in to any of our email services, we may send you occasional emails to keep you informed of golf-related products, services, information, contests or promotions or to provide you with the goods, services, website features or information that you requested. If you decide that you no longer wish to receive these emails, you will be given several ways to opt-out. This process is described in greater detail below.

If you provide us with your mailing address, telephone number or facsimile number, and tell us that we may contact you, we may also get in touch with you by one of these methods.

 **4\. Where does Callaway Golf store this information and is it secure?**  
Callaway Golf operates in many countries throughout the world. To enable us to offer consistent service to our customers, wherever they may live, we manage all of our Internet sites from one central location. This is currently in the United States of America. Information may be collected outside of the U.S. and transferred to the U.S. in certain instances. 

Callaway Golf takes precautions to protect your Personal Information, including our policy of allowing access to this Personal Information to only to those individuals and entities with a need to know. We also use available technology and encryption, when legally required or when appropriate for your protection, to provide a more secure environment and to reduce the chance of unauthorized access.

Personal Information is stored in a secure environment protected by a combination of physical and technical measures. The information may be kept in separate locations or it may be aggregated into reports, lists or databanks. There is no general public access to this information. In some cases, the Personal Information may be encrypted before you conduct your transaction, using appropriate secure technology. If you send us correspondence such as email or postal mail, or contact us by phone, we may collect such information in a file specific to you. These files will also be stored in secure locations.

Always keep in mind, however, that the Internet is not a secure system and you should always be cautious about the information you disclose while you are online. Although we take steps to protect your Personal Information against loss, misuse and alteration, as is the case with all computer networks linked to the Internet, we cannot absolutely guarantee the security of your Personal Information provided over the Internet and we will not be responsible for loss, misuse or alteration of the Personal Information.

 **5\. How long will Callaway Golf store this Personal Information?**  
We will remove the Personal Information within a reasonable period of time after receiving your request to do so. Otherwise, Callaway Golf will store this information in a secure and protected environment for as long as we believe it necessary to serve you and to carry out the other purposes for which we collected the Personal Information and General Data. In addition, legislation might oblige us to store this Personal Information for a certain period of time.

To understand how you can amend or update your Personal Information, please refer to the appropriate question in this Privacy Policy.

 **6\. Does Callaway Golf share this information with anyone?**  
We understand that your privacy is important to you. It is our policy not to disclose Personal Information about our website visitors without your explicit consent. This consent is given by your election to "opt-in" at the time you provide us with the Personal Information. Once you opt-in, you are granting us permission to use the Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy, including transferring to and storing your Personal Information at our central website located in the United States of America. Your election to opt-in also is your agreement that we may share your Personal Information with selected business partners and affiliates. The opt-in process further means that Callaway Golf and the entities that we share your Personal Information with (as described below) may contact you directly in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Whenever we share Personal Information pursuant to this Privacy Policy, we will inform the party receiving it that the Personal Information may only be used for a specific, limited purpose in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as agreed upon in advance by Callaway Golf (click here for more information on how your Personal Information may be used). We also may use confidentiality agreements to further protect Personal Information that becomes the property of Callaway Golf.

From time-to-time, in order to provide you with the services, information and products that you have requested, to conduct contests, promotions or sweepstakes or to provide you with services, information and products that we think might be of interest to you, we may share your Personal Information with the following entities and individuals:

 **Our Corporate Entities:** This includes Callaway Golf Company and our subsidiaries (collectively, the "Callaway Golf Companies"). Currently, Callaway Golf has subsidiaries in the United States, Canada, Europe, Japan, Korea and Australia. In addition to the Callaway Golf® brand of products, Callaway Golf's brands include, among others, Odyssey®, Top-Flite® and Ben Hogan®. To the extent that Personal Information is shared among the Callaway Golf Companies, or to the extent that one of our subsidiaries obtains your Personal Information directly from you, we will inform them that the Personal Information may only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In the event that one or more of the Callaway Golf Companies merges with, acquires or is acquired by another company, in whole or in part, we may also share information with this other business entity. If this occurs, we will require that this other business entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your Personal Information.  (References in this Privacy Policy to "Callaway Golf," "we" or "us" mean all of the Callaway Golf Companies. The privacy policies that apply to our various websites are very similar to this one, although you might find differences in the language depending on the country of origin of the particular website.)

 **Licensees, Licensors and other Business Partners:**   The Callaway Golf Companies may enter into business dealings, license agreements or other contracts with third parties (we call these relationships "Third Party Agreements"). In connection with these Third Party Agreements, the Callaway Golf Companies may license various trademarks and other intellectual property rights to third parties. At other times, Callaway Golf may receive permission from a third party to use the third party’s trademarks or intellectual property rights. In addition, Callaway Golf may enter into business relationships or contracts with other companies for a variety of goods and services. To the extent that Personal Information is shared with these third parties, we will inform them that the Personal Information may only be used for a specific, limited purpose in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as agreed upon in advance by Callaway Golf.

 **Marketing, Advertising and Website Hosting Companies:**   Occasionally, the Callaway Golf Companies utilize the services of outside agencies, companies or individuals to run marketing campaigns, respond to information requests, coordinate contests, sweepstakes and promotions or to host or operate websites and webpages that are connected with our business. We may also contract with third parties to help us better understand your web usage preferences or to analyze data that we collect on our websites and elsewhere. To the extent that Personal Information is shared with these third parties, we will inform them that the Personal Information may only be used for a specific, limited purpose in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as agreed upon in advance by Callaway Golf. 

**Consultants and Corporate Service Providers:**   The Callaway Golf Companies may use third parties to help us operate various aspects of our business. This might include people or companies that we bring in to help us understand how to more efficiently operate our business. It also might include third parties that we may use to outsource or help facilitate one or more aspects of our business (e.g. order fulfillment, customer service, co-branding issues, manufacturing, payment processing, etc.). To the extent that Personal Information is shared with these third parties, we will inform them that the Personal Information may only be used for a specific, limited purpose in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as agreed upon in advance by Callaway Golf.

 **Law Enforcement, Regulatory Agencies and Legal Proceedings:** The Callaway Golf Companies may share your information with government entities, authorized law enforcement personnel, regulatory bodies or as part of legal proceedings, in response to a valid subpoena or court order or as required by applicable law.  

**7\. What is the process for reviewing and correcting information?**  
You may request a copy of the Personal Information that Callaway Golf has collected. You may also correct any inaccuracies contained in this Personal Information. We do not charge for information requests, although we may charge you a fee to cover our reasonable costs of actually providing you with a copy of your Personal Information. We will require proof of your identity. Please address requests to Internet Customer Service Representative, Callaway Golf Company, 2180 Rutherford Road, Carlsbad, California 92008-7328 or email [](mailto:webmaster@callawaygolf.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Question)[webmaster@callawaygolf.com](mailto:webmaster@callawaygolf.com?).  We will provide you with a readable copy of the Personal Information within a reasonable time period after your request (usually 30 days, although we will acknowledge your request within 14 days). You may challenge the data that we hold about you, and, where appropriate, you may have the data corrected or completed. In some instances recognized by law, we may refuse to provide you with a copy of the Personal Information or change the data, but we will give you reasons for our refusal. 

We also welcome your questions, comments and suggestions about our Privacy Policy. Please send your comments to [](mailto:webmaster@callawaygolf.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Question)[webmaster@callawaygolf.com](mailto:webmaster@callawaygolf.com).

 **8\. Does Callaway Golf offer links to other websites?**  
We also may offer links to websites that are not operated by Callaway Golf. If you visit one of these linked sites, you should review their privacy and other policies. We are not responsible for the policies and practices of other companies. Similarly, while all websites operated by the Callaway Golf Companies have similar privacy policies that govern their use and operation, policies may vary from site to site based upon local customs, practices or laws or due to circumstances unique to that site. Please review the privacy policy of each site to determine the privacy policies of that site.

 **9\. What about Personal Information received from third parties?  
**  
Any Personal Information that Callaway Golf receives from third parties is subject to the privacy polices of those entities. We are not responsible for the policies and practices of other companies. You should carefully review the privacy policy of any third party to make sure you are comfortable with how they are going to treat your personal data. For example, some companies may require you to opt-out of their information exchange programs. In those instances, Callaway Golf may receive and/or use information gathered by these outside companies or agencies, and the handling and processing of your data will be governed by such third parties’ policies and not by this Callaway Golf policy.

 **10\. What about the privacy of children?**  
Protecting the privacy of children is important. Our website is not directed at children under the age of 13, nor do we knowingly solicit or collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that a user is under the age of 13 and has signed up without prior verifiable parental consent, we will remove his or her Personal Information from our files.

 **11\. What happens if Personal Information is not provided?**

If you choose not to provide Personal Information, you will still, in most cases, be able to use many of the website features. However you will not be able to access areas that require registration or participate over the Internet in contests, sweepstakes or similar promotions.

Even if you do not provide Personal Information, we will sometimes collect anonymous information about how you have used the website. This is information that does not personally identify you, but which may be helpful for marketing or improving the services we offer. (See link for more information on general data that is collected when you visit our websites and on how we use cookies.)

 **12\. How can I stop receiving communications from Callaway Golf?**   
If you wish to stop receiving communications from us or would like us to cease processing your information in any other way, you can write to us at: Internet Customer Service Representative, Callaway Golf Company, 2180 Rutherford Road, Carlsbad, California 92008-7328 or email [](mailto:webmaster@callawaygolf.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Question)[webmaster@callawaygolf.com](mailto:webmaster@callawaygolf.com).

We will also provide you with a return email opt-out address in each email that we send to you so that you may opt out of receiving future email communications. This return opt-out address will be operational for at least 30 days following the date the email was originally sent to you.

 **13\. What happens when changes are made to this Privacy Policy?**  
From time to time, it may be necessary for Callaway Golf to change this privacy policy. We suggest that you check here periodically. Such modifications will automatically be effective 30 days after they are initially posted on the website. You can be assured, however, that any changes will not be retroactively applied and will not alter how we handle previously collected information.

Please see our terms and conditions for additional information.

 **14\. When was the Privacy Policy last updated and when do those changes take effect?**  
This Privacy Policy is effective February 16, 2004. There have been no updates to this Privacy Policy since that date.  If we obtained your name prior to February 16, 2004, and if you have not expressly consented to be subject to the Privacy Policy set forth above, please click here to view the privacy policy that applies to your personal information.
